Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publications File (Continued)
  - 1971-1972
    - A tribute to a mere magazine by a great man. In Arizona Highways (vol.47, no.12), December 1971.; (p.48) (Box 80)
      [Excerpt from Arizona the Wrinkled land in Books West Southwest. Ritchie, 1956.]
    - Exploring Arizona's literary trails. In Arizona Highways (vol.48, no.9), September 1972.; (p.16) (Box 80)
    - John E. Goodwin: Founder of the UCLA Library. An essay toward a biography. Friends of the UCLA Library, [reprint from: Journal of Library History, ]., 1972. July 1971 (Box 80)
    - Reading San Diego. In San Diego and the Back Country. edited by Davis Dutton. New York: Ballantine books, 1972. (Box 80)
    - School of Library Science--Distinguished librarian on faculty. In Education Newsletter vol.10, no.4. University of Arizona, March 1972.; (p.3) (Box 80)
    - Highlights of survey recommendation. A Survey of the Library of the University Of Arizona. By R.C.Swank, Page Ackerman, Melvin J. Voigt. Tucson, University of Arizona, 1972. (Box 80)
    - Theodore M. Lilienthal. Roxburghe & Zamorano Club, (a memorial)., 1972 (Box 80)
- Lawrence Clark Powell Tape Recordings
  This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Gilman Party, July 17-18, 1954. (Box 81)
    Featuring LCP on piano, various drunken and singing voices. 2 tapes for each evening.
  - Gerhart Muench playing the music of Scriabin, UCLA, LCP introduces program., July 15, 1953.; (2 tapes) (Box 81)
    (See box 24 for typescript of introduction)
    - Gerhart Muench playing the music of Scriabin, UCLA, LCP introduces program, 1953 July 15; yrlsc_0229_081_001a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:23:12) 7 inches (Box 81, Case 1)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
      Scope and Contents
      Content note: Reel 1 of 2. Tracks 1 and 3
    - Gerhart Muench playing the music of Scriabin, UCLA, LCP introduces program, 1953 July 15; yrlsc_0229_081_001b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:24:05) 7 inches (Box 81, Case 1)
      Content note: Reel 1 of 2. Tracks 1 and 4
    - Gerhart Muench playing the music of Scriabin, UCLA, LCP introduces program, 1953 July 15; yrlsc_0229_081_002a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:33) 7 inches (Box 81, Case 2)
      Content note: Reel 2 of 2. Track 2
  - Lecture, followed by discussion, at the College of Librarianship, Wales., November 22, 1966.; (1 tape, 3.75 i.p.s) (Box 81)
  - Libraries in the Southwest. Recordings of conference., 1955; (6 reels) (Box 81)
    (See box 75 for LCP's file on conference)
- Manuscripts Of Articles And Lectures, ca. 1950-1971
  - Boxes 83-104
    (Manuscripts in alphabetical order)
    - A - An
      - ABBA Talk, October 14, 1970. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Aberystwyth talk, November 1966. (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - About poetry. Friday Morning Club, May 23, 1950. (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Academic Library notes. CLA Bulletin, 1939-1949. (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Act of Enchantment. Historical Society of New Mexico, November 19, 1960. (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Administration in One Easy Lesson. CLA - SORT--Long Beach, October 30, 1968. (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Adventures in Discrimination. Kern County Free Library, Bakersfield, February 14, 1950. (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Adventures with a Biblio-Geiger Counter. Friends of the Detroit Public Library, May 5, 1953. (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Ainsworth, K. Retirement Talk--Monrovia Public Library, July 23, 1967. (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - An Alchemist of Books. 'B. Marshall for Bulletin of Bibliogra1/2ju. (Box 83, Folder 10)
      - Alchemy of Books. ALA, New York, June 30, 1952; Dallas Public Library, September 24, 1956. (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - R.A. in Los Angeles Southern Illinois University, sent, April 1964. (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - All that is Poetic in Life. Friends South Pasadena Public Library, ALA Annual, Sacramento; Los Angeles Severance Club. (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - All That is Poetic in Life. In Wilson Library Bulletin. (Box 83, Folder 14)
      - An Almanac for Librarians. In Wilson Library Bulletin, June 1945. (Box 83, Folder 15)
      - American in California--Preface by LCP on Andrew Rolle's book., June 1965 (Box 83, Folder 16)
      - American Libraries--LCP letters, April 1971-October 1972. (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - Review of W. Munthe's American Librarianship from a European Angle. Sent to Library Journal, 15 July, 1964. (Box 83, Folder 18)
      - Andrew H. Horn. California Librarian, July 1966. (Box 83, Folder 19)
      - Angel's Flight. In Hoja Volante, 1954. (Box 83, Folder 20)
      - Announcement. American Library Association General Session, June 26, 1953. (Box 83, Folder 21)
      - Antiquarian Bookfair Keepsake... Foreword by LCP, October 1965. (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Ar - Book H
      - Arizona Highways, Correspondence. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Arizona Librarian, 1968. (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Arizona St. Library Association. Phoenix, March 23, 1971. (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - Arizona University Library talk, May 1971. (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - Arizona University Press, Bourne manuscript approval, 1971. (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - Around the World in Sixty Books. (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Art of Librarianship, World Publishing Company. (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - Association, ABA London and Manchester, May 16, 1951 March 5, 1951. (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - At the Heart of the Matter. UCLA University Affiliates, January 23, 1957. (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - Austin, Mary. Dedication for Arizona and the West, 1967-68. (Box 84, Folder 10)
      - Authors' Club (untitled). Hollywood Roosevelt, December 12, 1956. (Box 84, Folder 11)
      - Barleyfields, Buildings, and Books. Women's Faculty Club, October 19, 1954. (Box 84, Folder 12)
      - Basic Home Library for the College Graduate. In Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, July 1962. (Box 84, Folder 13)
      - Bay State Librarian interview, 1968. (Box 84, Folder 14)
      - Beanfields, Builders, and Books. Historical Society of Southern California Quarterly, Spring 1955. (Box 84, Folder 15)
      - Beautiful Byways of Southern California. Friends of the Monrovia Public Library, November 13, 1962. (Box 84, Folder 16)
      - Bennett, Melba, Foreword to her book. (Box 84, Folder 17)
      - Bennett, M.B. obituary, December 28, 1969. (Box 84, Folder 18)
      - Bibliographers of the Golden State. Los Angeles, April 17, 1967. (Box 84, Folder 19)
      - Bibliography of Gregg Anderson. Tributes of Columbrad, R&C. Zamorano Roxburghe, 1949. (Box 84, Folder 20)
      - Bibliography--Lawrence Clark Powell. Library Literature. (Box 84, Folder 21)
      - Bibliography of His Published Writings. Lawrence Clark Powell. (Box 84, Folder 22)
      - Bieler, Henry G. Foreword by LCP, October 1964 and July 1972. (Box 84, Folder 23)
      - Biography--Lawrence Clark Powell. (Box 84, Folder 24)
      - Book Collecting. Los Angeles County Museum, Prytanean; Avalon Rotary Club, November 1948. (Box 84, Folder 25)
      - Book Collecting and Libraries. In Antiquarian Bookman. (Box 84, Folder 26)
      - Book Hunting in Britain. In Westways, October 1951. (Box 84, Folder 27)
      - Book Hunter in Britain. In California Librarian, March 1951. (Box 84, Folder 28)
      - Book Hunter in Britain. (outline for book). (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - Book - I - Books
      - Bookman Abroad. Severance Club, December 13, 1957. (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Bookman and Humanist. Wyer, Malcolm, Glenn; Review by LCP in Library Journal. (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - Bookman in Orbit. Santa Monica Friends, June 14, 1961. (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - Bookman in Seven League Books. In Southwest Review, 1958. (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - Bookman Looks at Life. USC School of Medicine, December 12, 1957. (Box 85, Folder 5)
      - Bookman's Progress, 1968. (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - Bookplates--Preface for L.S. Jones, August 5, 1950. (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Book Reviews. (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - Book Reviews--Various by LCP. (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - Books and Book Collectors--John Carter BSA Papers. (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - Books Determine. Southwest Library Association. Albuquerque, November 1954. (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Books Determine. In Wilson Library Bulletin, September 1955. (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - Books and Reading. Long Beach Public Library, January 15, 1957. (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - Books and Traditions, First 25 Years at UCLA. Intersorority Mothers' Club, May 24, 1955. (Box 85, Folder 14)
      - Books are my Life Raft. Utah Library Association Convention. (Box 85, Folder 15)
      - Books, a Way of Life. (Box 85, Folder 16)
      - Books Excite. (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - Books for Your Baggage. In Westways, April 1966. (Box 85, Folder 18)
      - Books I Have Enjoyed. In Montana Library Quarterly, October 1959. (Box 85, Folder 19)
      - Book in My Baggage. (Box 85, Folder 20)
      - Books in My Life. UCLA University Affiliates, October 27, 1958. (Box 85, Folder 21)
      - Books of the Southwest. (Box 85, Folder 22)
      - Books of the Land. In California Library Bulletin, February 50. (Box 85, Folder 23)
      - Books, People, and the Earth on Which We Live. Vancouver, August 1949. (Box 85, Folder 24)
      - Books, People, and the Earth on Which We Live. In Wilson Library Bulletin, February 1950. (Box 85, Folder 25)
      - Books Pinon Nuts, and Shadow. In Arizona Highways, August 1953. (Box 85, Folder 26)
      - Books That Weren't in My Baggage. In New York Times Book Review, 1963. (Box 85, Folder 27)
      - Book Thoughts from Abroad. In California Librarian, June 1951. (Box 85, Folder 28)
      - Books West Southwest. Ward Ritchie Press, 1957. (Box 85, Folder 29)
      - Books Will Be Read. Annual Lecture, Library Association. (Box 85, Folder 30)
    - Booth - Car
      - Booth, B.A. Memorial, 1970. (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Bowker Critique, 1972. (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Boy, A Library and a Life. Friends of the Sierra Madre Library, June 2, 1955. (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Boyhood Reading. San Rafael PTA Meeting and Book Fair, March 21, 1956. (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Bradbury, Ray, Introduction. CLA, October 21, 1959. (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Breed, Clara; Luncheon talk. San Diego, May 27, 1970. (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Breeding and Care of 3H Librarians. Enoch Pratt Free Library. Baltimore, November 23, 1962. (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Broadcast, University Explorer, and Brown, Ralph A., R.F. Stevens and Brown, UCLA Librarian Memoriam., June 15, 1955 and October 16, 1955.... (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - Browning Society. Marin County, February 6, 1962. (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - Browning and New Mexico. San Francisco Browning Society, January 4, 1957. (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - Browning. San Francisco Browning Society, February 29, 1952. (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - Browning Society. San Francisco, 1953. (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - Browning Society, January 4, 1963. (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Building With Books. Dedication of the Hunt Library; Carnegie Institute of Technology; Carnegie Institute of Technology, October 1961. (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - Building With Books. In Alumni Magazine, Carnegie Tech. (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - CALibrarian. (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - California. American Oxford Encyclopedia, January 15, 1963. (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - California Bicentennial Lecture. Riverside, November 2, 1969. (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - A California Bookman Abroad. In California Librarian, October 1950. (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - California Literature, 1950. Los Angeles City College Lecture Series, July 24, 1950. (Box 86, Folder 20)
      - California Literature. University Extension. Dawson Bookshop, November 8, 1955. (Box 86, Folder 21)
      - California Local History. Review for College and Research Libraries, September 1970. (Box 86, Folder 22)
      - California, University of Los Angeles Junior college library national conference,, LCP moderator-panel., July 12-14, 1965 (Box 86, Folder 23)
      - Californian in Connecticut., April 8, 1968. (Box 86, Folder 24)
      - California, University, San Diego, Seminar in Librarianship, April 19, 1965. (Box 86, Folder 25)
      - Care and Feeding of the Bookish Administrator. LCP Library Journal, December 1957. (Box 86, Folder 26)
      - Care and Feeding of the Bookish Administrator. LCP Inst. for Library Administration, August 9, 1957. (Box 86, Folder 27)
      - Carrying Vines to Visalia. Yosemite District. CLA, Wilson Library Bulletin, California Library Bulletin., April 24, 1948. (Box 86, Folder 28)
    - Cas - Dea
      - Casanova--Child's evaluation of manuscript., August 1968. (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Castagna, Profile of. In Library Journal, June 1962. (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Cathedrals and Bookshops. In Hoja Volante, July 1952. (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Cavalcade of Books. KNXT, Reviews given, December 26, 1954. (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Chandler, Raymond, Foreword to. Written by LCP to be published in a book on Chandler by A.A. Knopf. (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Change of Pace. California Library Association, October 4, 1951. (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - The Chief Librarian: Bookman or Administrator? Slechert-Hafner Book News, November 1948. (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Clark Collection of Oscar Wilde. Campus Theater, January 1970. (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Clark, Harold Haines, Eulogy, Also printed., April 3, 1964. (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Clark Library. UCLA Alumni Magazine, April 23, 1945. (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Clark Library. Dawson's Bookshop, Extension Lecture Series, November 9, 1954. (Box 87, Folder 11)
      - Clark Library and its Rescources. Clark Library Zamorano Club, May 3, 1944. (Box 87, Folder 12)
      - Collected Works of Henry R. Wagner. Foreword, Ward Ritchie Press. (Box 87, Folder 13)
      - Collections of Books. UC Riverside, February 24, 1955. (Box 87, Folder 14)
      - College in My Life. In Occidental Alumnus, January 1952. (Box 87, Folder 15)
      - Collison's Street Lit Foreword, 1972. (Box 87, Folder 16)
      - Collison, Class,, SLS., December 8, 1971 (Box 87, Folder 17)
      - Come Hither. (Box 87, Folder 18)
      - Connecticut Library Association. New Haven, April 18, 1968. (Box 87, Folder 19)
      - Continent's End. AAUW, January 8, 1944. (Box 87, Folder 20)
      - Controversial Literature in the University Library. CLA South District, UCLA, 1949. (Box 87, Folder 21)
      - Cornell, Ralph. Memorial, 1972. (Box 87, Folder 22)
      - Coulter Lecture. (Box 87, Folder 23)
      - Covey, Alan D., Published by Arizona Librarian. (Box 87, Folder 24)
      - Crabtree Letter, Los Angeles Times, September 1960. (Box 87, Folder 25)
      - D.A.B. (Dictionary of American Biography). (Box 87, Folder 26)
      - Dabagh, Thomas S., in Memoriam. California Librarian, July 1959. (Box 87, Folder 27)
      - Dana Review. Southern California Quarterly, March 1965. (Box 87, Folder 28)
      - Dark Spring, Bright Spring. Tucson, May 4, 1971. (Box 87, Folder 29)
      - Davis, UC, talk, California Classics, April 12, 1970. (Box 87, Folder 30)
      - Dawson Bookshop Dedication, August 23, 1968. (Box 87, Folder 31)
      - Death Valley. Foreword by LCP. Ward Ritchie Press, February 1962. (Box 87, Folder 32)
    - Deg - Fm
      - Degolyer Foundation, report to. (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Denver, University of. School of Librarianship, April 5-7, 1961. (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Dickson, Edward A. UCLA Librarian, March 9, 1952. (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Dickson, Edward A. Schoenburg Hall, Dickson Memorial Services, March 5, 1956. (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Dickson, Edward A. History of UCLA, Foreword by LCP. (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Drake, Dorothy. Tribute, 1969. (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Did Drake Duck L.A.? San Francisco: Zamorano-Roxburghe, September 8, 1956. (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - Discussion Group Talk, by LCP., July 9, 1943 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Dixon, Maynard, sketchbook, foreword, September 1967. (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Dobie, J. Frank., September 1964, Austin American Statesman. (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Dobie, J. Frank. Article for Arizona Highways. (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Double Marriage of Robinson Jeffers, Summer 1956. (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Down Where the Rockies End. PNLA Joint Meeting. Denver, September 3, 1965. (Box 88, Folder 13)
      - Downs, R.B. Books That Changed America.. (Box 88, Folder 14)
      - Dreaming and Doing. In The CALibrarian,, UCLA Affiliates, Spring 1962 February 8, 1962. (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Drexel Award, March 1968. (Box 88, Folder 16)
      - Education for Academic Librarianship. Institute Graduate Library School, Chicago University, ALA, August 1948. (Box 88, Folder 17)
      - Education for Librarianship Abroad in Selected Countries (Library Trends). Lancour and Harrison in Library Journal, March 1964. (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - Education of a Librarian. Annapolis: Maryland Library Association, May 1954. (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Education of an Educator. Speech--Publication Library Journal, September 27, 1963. (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - The Eightieth Catalogue. Remarkable Manuscripts, Books and Maps from the Ninth to the Eighteenth Century. Draus review by LCP, Library Quarterly., February 1957. (Box 88, Folder 21)
      - Elements of a Good Librarian. In Wilson Library Bulletin, November 1958. (Box 88, Folder 22)
      - Elements of a Good Librarian. Ohio/Indiana Association; School Library Association of California. (Box 88, Folder 23)
      - Elements of Fruitfulness. In Antiquarian Booksellers' Association Annual, 1956. (Box 88, Folder 24)
      - Slater's El Morro--foreword. (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - En - F
      - Encyclopedias Review. (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Engineering Executive Talks, UCLA Engineering Department, 1959,60. (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - English Department. Affiliates,, California Classics Talk., November 1970 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - England, 1954. (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Eshelman, William R. The CALibrarian, July 1960. (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Essences of Britain. ABA Annual, 1953. (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Essences of Britain. (Box 89, Folder 7)
        (See list in folder)
      - Eucalyptus trees and lost manuscripts. In Los Angeles Times. (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Ewing, Majl, obituary., for Hoja Volante., December 1967 (Box 89, Folder 9)
      - Exhibit Policy in the Library, November 27, 1951. (Box 89, Folder 10)
      - The Fate of a Plate. In Hoja Volante, August, 1954. (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - Federal Music Library at UCLA. Institute on Music, September 15, 1944. (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Ferguson, Erna, a profile. In New Mexico Magazine. (Box 89, Folder 13)
      - Fifty Good Books on New Mexico. In New Mexico Magazine. (Box 89, Folder 14)
      - Financial Problems of College and University Libraries. CURLS, CLA. Long Beach, October 13, 1954. (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - First Book Printed in Guatamala, 1663. Book Club of California Keepsake, 1956. (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - Foundations of the Public Library, Review of, by LCP for Library Journal, June 1965. (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - Fountains in the Sand. (Box 89, Folder 18)
      - Fortune and Friendship. (Box 89, Folder 19)
      - Four Very Short Stories. Faculty Club, USC, December 7, 1955. (Box 89, Folder 20)
        (Plus other talks--see list in this folder)
      - Friends' Day Address, UCLA Friends of the Library., 1951. (Box 89, Folder 21)
      - Free Flow of Books. English Speaking Union, Edinburgh,; California Librarian,; Journal of the National Book League, March 1951 October 15, 1951 June 1951. (Box 89, Folder 22)
      - Friends of the LAPL (Los Angeles Public Library)., April 19, 1971. (Box 89, Folder 23)
      - Friends of the San Francisco Public Library. c/o Columbia-Geneva Stell Division, San Francisco 6, California., October 30, 1961. (Box 89, Folder 24)
      - From Private Collection to Public Institution: The Transformation of the Clark Library. In Library Quarterly, April 1950. (Box 89, Folder 25)
      - Fulbright project,, unpublished., 1954 (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - G - Hona
      - Giff to be Simple. Greenville: South Carolina Public Library, October 1956. (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Gift to be Simple. In Library Journal. (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Gillis, Mabel, obituary. (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Go Forth and Be Useful. SLS Commencement., June 8, 1962. (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Golden Apples and Cherry Blossoms. (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Grass Roots Librarianship. USC Library School, March 7, 1956. (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Great American Nature Writer: Donald Culross Peattie. Phi Gamma Delta, June 1945. (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Great Land of Libraries. ALA Detroit, July 1965. (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Guide to Special Collections, Foreword, LCP, Summer 1958. (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Guggenheim file, 1967. (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - Hail to the Chief (Preface to Know Your Library), 1954. (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Eulogy in Farewells to Phil Townsend, June 4, 1957. (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Happiness is a Stall in Zurich. (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Heart of the Southwest (Bibliography), March 1955. (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - Hoja Volante, 1960. (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Heart of the Southwest. Ventura County Institute. Ojai Valley, December 4, 1957. (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Heart of the Southwest (Revised) In Arizona Highways, March 1957. (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Henry the First. Henry R. Wagner Eulogy. Forest Lawn, April 1, 1957. (Box 90, Folder 18)
      - Heritage of the Southwest. Phoenix Executives Club, March 15, 1957. (Box 90, Folder 19)
      - Homage to the Big Sur. In Hoja Volante, 1955. (Box 90, Folder 20)
      - Homage to Browning. In California Librarian, November 4, 1952. (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Home - Jn
      - Home Thoughts from Abroad. Santa Barbara,; Santa Cruz, January 31, 1967 May 27, 1967. (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Horgan, Paul. The Horgan File, New York Times, March 1967. May 14, 1967. (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - The Importance of the Library in Higher Education. UCLA - Engineering - Gadjah Mada Project Seminar - Conference Center. Arrowhead, June 1964. (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Huxley, Aldous memorial (printed by Hartzberger) as spoken & as printed. (LCP, Kirsch and Zeitlin), February 1964. (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - In it Together. ABBA, In Antiquarian Bookman, Spring 1949. 1949. (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - In Praise of English Books. Books of the Month (English), October 1952. (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - In Quest of Orpheus. Catholic Library Association, College of Notre Dame. Belmont, California, November 1961. (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - In Quest of Orpheus. Catholic Library Association, College of Notre Dame. Belmont, California, October 28, 1961. (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - In Search of Spring, In Hoja Volante and Southwest Review., September 1963. (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - Into the Mainstream. 52nd Conference S.L.A. S. Francisco, Library Journal. (Box 91, Folder 10)
      - The Intimate Henry Miller. Introduction by LCP New American Library of World Literature. Signet., April 1959. (Box 91, Folder 11)
      - I Should Like to Rise and Go. Occidental College Publication, 1961. (Box 91, Folder 12)
      - Inland Empire. Rialto, March 21, 1952. (Box 91, Folder 13)